A Guide to the Records of the Secretary of the Commonwealth: Requests for Pardons and Restoration of Rights, 2001-2013 (bulk 2010-2013)
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Records of the Secretary of the Commonwealth: Requests for Pardons and Restoration of Rights, 2001-2013 (bulk 2010-2013)
The Library of Virginia
51134
13 cu. ft. (13 boxes)
Virginia Secretary of the Commonwealth
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
This collection is restricted for 75 years (2085) due to privacy protected information. COV 2.2-3706; 16.1-305; 2.2-3801; 42.1-78
Acquisition Information
Transferred from the Virginia Secretary of Administration on January 23, 2014.
Historical Information
Robert F. McDonnell was elected 71st governor of the Commonwealth of Virginia in November 2009 and inaugurated on 16 January 2010. He served until 11 January 2014. Janet Vestal Kelly (formerly Janet Polarek until 2012) served as the Secretary of the Commonwealth throughout McDonnell's tenure. She had previously served as the Chief Operations Officer during his gubernatorial campaign and as a staff member while McDonnell served as Attorney General.
The Office of the Secretary of the Commonwealth has evolved from early colonial times when there existed a Secretary of the Colony. The Office became a gubernatorial appointment subsequent to a 1958 Act of the Assembly. The Secretary of the previous hit Commonwealth next hit is under the jurisdiction of the Governor's Office. The Secretary is appointed by the Governor for a term of four years. Currently the Secretary of the Commonwealth is responsible for gubernatorial appointments, clemency and restoration of civil rights requests and extraditions. Other responsibilities include authenticating and certifying the records of the courts and of any state agency.
Scope and Content
This collection consists primarily of correspondence from petitioners requesting either a pardon, clemency, or the restoration of rights. It also includes supporting documentation from petitioners, as well as correspondence between agencies and the Parole Board.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into two series:
Series I: Pardons
Series II: Restoration of Rights
Contents List
- Series I. Pardons, 2001-2013., Extent: 12 boxes (12 cu. ft.). (Boxes 1-12)
  Folders are arranged alphabetically by last name when possible.
  - 2001-2007. (Box 1)
  - A-Z, 2008. (Box 2)
  - A-Z, 2009. (Box 3)
  - A-J, 2010. (Box 4)
  - K-S, 2010. (Box 5)
  - T-Z, 2010. (Box 6)
  - A-L 2011. (Box 7)
  - M-Z 2011. (Box 8)
  - A-L, 2012. (Box 9)
  - M-Z, 2012. (Box 10)
  - A-N, 2013. (Box 11)
  - O-Z, 2013. (Box 12)
- Series I. Restoration of Rights,, 2010-2013., Extent: 1 box (1 cu. ft.). (Box 13)
  Folders are arranged chronologically.
  - Restoration of Rights, 2010-2013. (Box 13)